Guide to the Cornell University Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender Resource Center records,1991-2007.
Cornell University Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender Resource Center records,1991-2007
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cornell University Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender Resource Center records, 1991-2007.
53-23-3192
Cornell University.Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender Resource Center.
2.4 cubic feet
Working files, printed material.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
The collection contains files on the establishment of the Resource Office in 1994-1995 and its activities and events through 2010; annual and monthly reports; files on fall retreats; files on the production of a newsletter; files on specific events, subgroups, and activities, including Dialogue, a group on religion (1995-97), sexuality conferences (1995-97), posters and event planning documents; files on Resource Center history and specific issues, including an overall program review in the spring of 1997, the name change in 1998, a file on hate mail and acts of homophobia (1994-99), and a file on controversy over the teaching of a particular class by Prof. Ellis Hanson in 1997 or 1998.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
Cornell established the Lesbian, Gay and Bisexual Resource Office in 1994 to serve the entire campus community: students, staff, and faculty. In the Spring of 1998, its name changed to Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender Resource Center. Susie Lerner (1994-1995), Carlisle Douglas (1995-1998), and Gwendolyn Dean (1998-2008) have led the office as coordinators or director.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Files on the establishment of the Resource Office in 1994-1995; annual and monthly reports; files on fall retreats; files on the production of a newsletter; files on specific events, subgroups, and activities, including Dialogue, a group on religion (1995-1997), sexuality conferences (1995-1997), posters and event planning documents; files on Resource Center history and specific issues, including an overall program review in the spring of 1997, the name change in 1998, a file on hate mail and acts of homophobia (1994-1999), and a file on controversy over the teaching of a particular class by Prof. Ellis Hanson in 1997 or 1998.
Also, files on other LBGT-related Cornell organizations and offices: the establishment of Haven, a program in the Dean of Students Office to serve the counseling and social support needs of Cornell LBGT students and those questioning their sexuality, 1995-2006; files from CUGALA, Cornell University Gay and Lesbian Alumni Association, and an alumni survey, 1995-1998. And some files on relevant past events, including Tompkins County Local Law 6 in 1991, the issue of a GLB Living-Learning Unit at Cornell in 1994, and a Cornell Town Meeting on LGBT Issues in 1996.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University. Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender Resource Center.; Dean, Gwendolyn.; Douglas, Carlisle.; Hanson, Ellis, 1965-; Lerner, Susie.; Cornell University--Students.; Cornell University--Employees.; Cornell University--Faculty.; Cornell University. Lesbian, Gay and Bisexual Resource Office.
Subjects:
Gay college students.; Gay liberation movement.; Lesbians.; Gay men.; Gays.; Homosexuality.; Bisexuals.; Bisexuality.; Gender identity.; Transsexuals.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
Collecting program: Human Sexuality Collection.
CONTAINER LIST
- Annual report and files from Heather Allore, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Annual reports, 1994-1998 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Coordinator's monthly report (Carlisle Douglas), 1994-1998 (Box 1, Folder 2a)
- LGBRO Annual report, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Retreat and "Jumpin' Thru Hoops" information, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Fall retreat, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Retreat publicity, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Retreat, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Community building notes/designs (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Handouts and other print (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Jumping Through Hoops (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Compiled Retreat evaluations, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Jumping Through Hoops materials, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Jumping Through Hoops, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Retreat, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Retreat support groups, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Retreat publicity, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Retreat program planning, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Retreat- Jumpin' Thru Hoops, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Retreat, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Retreat, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Newsletter vol. 1, Spring 1998 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Dialogue, Fall 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Dialogue, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Old LGBRC posters/fliers (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Campus sexuality conferences, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Conference handout- "Queer Survivors: A Conference on Abuse and Sexual Identity", Nov. 15, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- TransPositions (Box 1, Folder 27)
- RC event planning, Jan.-June 2000 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- RC History: Inclusion report (Box 1, Folder 29)
- RC History: LGBRO review, Spring 1997 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- RC History: Review documents (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Name change, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Hate mail and documentation of anti-gay acts on campus, 1994-1999 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Controversy around Prof. Ellis Hanson's course, "The Sexual Child", 1997/1998 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- ZAP! (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Gay youth and other volunteer opportunities, 1995-1997 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Local professionals (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Working group, 1995-1997 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Town meeting, April 11, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- CUGALA and Alumni Survey (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Reunion, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- CUGALA midwinter meeting, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Monthly reports and misc., 1994-1997 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Goals/plans/timelines (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Queer Peer Counseling program, HAVEN, 1995-1998 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Misc., 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Misc., 1996-1998 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Establishing office Year 1 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Living In: Lesbian, Gay, & Bisexual Families: a photographic-text exhibit, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- LBQ, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 50)
- Photos of Alum, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Student Coalition Against Racism, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 52)
- RC Publicity, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 53)
- Tompkins Co. Local Law 6, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 54)
- Heather Allore Speech - Town Meeting on LGBT issues at Cornell University, April 11, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 55)
- CU GLB Living Learning Unit, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 56)
- LLU (Box 1, Folder 57)
- Notes to New LGBT RC Coordinator, by Carlisle Douglas, May 1998 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Strategic Planning, Spring 1998 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- National Day of Silence Photos, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- RC Newsletter, 1999-2000 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Campus Events, ca. 2005-2006 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Clippings etc. re LGBT campus service, 2000-2007 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Flyers, clippings on LGBT topics, 2000-2007 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Cornell LGBT and diversity issues (Box 2, Folder 8)
- CU HR Issues (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Speech at Southern Tier NY Pride (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Plans for LGBT RC Library (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Workshop on Organizational Changes, 2002-2003 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- RC Assessment, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Haven Constitution (Box 2, Folder 14)
- DOS, Haven leadership training, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- National Day of Silence Photographs (Box 2, Folder 16)
- National Day of Silence Photographs B (Box 2, Folder 17)
- "A Silent Tribute," Created Equal, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Brochures and Booklets (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Flyers and Advertising Cards (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Southern Tier AIDS Program Brochures (Box 2, Folder 21)
- PFLAG Brochures and Booklets (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Planned Parenthood Brochures (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Resource Packets (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Life Cycles: Quality of Life Programs for Staff and Faculty (Cornell University) (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Cornell TransPositions Conference (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Articles and Newspaper Clippings (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Office Manager Report to Advisory Board, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- RC Planning and Correspondence, 2005-2007 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Calendars, Events, and Publicity, 1995-2002 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Andrew Kopkind '57 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Evangelicals Concerned (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Training Materials (1) (Box 2, Folder 33a)
- Training Materials (2) (Box 2, Folder 33b)
- Solidarity in Action: A Historical Scrapbook (Box 2, Folder 34)
- RC General Fliers (Box 2, Folder 35)
- LGBT RC Campus Events, ca. 2003-2005 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Other Campus Events, ca. 2002-2009 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Health and General LGBT Resource Pamphlets, ca. 1990-2010 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Campus Events, 2002-2010 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- New England Leather Alliance pamphlets, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Women's Heath Brochures (Box 2, Folder 41)
- General Health Brochures (Box 2, Folder 42)
- LGBT Brochures and Information (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Information Pamphlets for Gay Men (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Mind-Altering Drug Series Pamphlets (Box 2, Folder 45)
- Gay Asian and Pacific Islander Men of New York Pamphlets, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 46)
- Gay, Lesbian, and Straight Education Network Publications, 2003-2004 (Box 2, Folder 47)
- Parents, Families and Friends of Lesbians and Gays Publications, 1994-2002 (Box 2, Folder 48)
- HIV Information Pamphlets, 1995-2002 (Box 2, Folder 49)
- LGBT Pamphlets in Spanish, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 50)
- Protecting Students from Harassment and Hate Crime - A Guide for Schools, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 51)
- Cornell LGBT Resources and Support Brochure, event ephemera including items related to the Farewell to Friends event, 30th Anniversary of Student Homophile League, and a 1998 rainbow tassel, 1997-1998 (Box 2, Folder 52)
- Filthy/Gorgeous Posters, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Filthy/Gorgeous Posters, 2008 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Filthy/Gorgeous Posters, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Filthy/Gorgeous Posters, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- LGBT Campus Event Posters (Large), 2005-2010 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Bisexuality Resource Packet in Braille - part one, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  Includes printed copy
- Bisexuality Resource Packet in Braille - part two, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Our Trans Children in Braille, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender Resource Center Flyer in Braille (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Creating A Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender-Affirming Workplace at Cornell University Flyer in Braille (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Causes in Common: Reproductive Rights and LGBT Liberation Pamphlet in Braille, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  Includes printed pamphlet
- Out for a change: Addressing homophobia in women's sports, 1994; V-5994 (Box 4)
  Includes printed curriculum
- Large posters concerning Cornell LGBTQ events, including concerts, drag shows, and talks., 2000-2009 (Map-case DD-14)